Mss.B.W243 Mss.B.W243
American Philosophical Society
John Warner letters and papers, 1850-1864
Mss.B.W243
American Philosophical Society
255.0 Item(s)
The major portion of this correspondence deals with the controversy which arose when Benjamin Peirce, after having seen the manuscript of Warner's "Studies in Organic Morphology" (Philadelphia, 1857), read a paper on morphology before the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1855). Other topics discussed include the alleged "Harvard clique," the administration of the Dudley Observatory (Albany, N.Y.), and the United States Coast and Geodetic Survey.
255 items.
Warner, John,d. 1873.
Box 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Deposited by the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, 1944.
Biographical/Historical note
John Warner was an amateur mathematician and naturalist (d. 1873) who resided in Pottsville, Pennsylvania. He published on engineering subjects and organic morphology. He lived abroad from 1862 to 1868, visiting England, France, Italy, the Levant, Egypt, Greece, Constantinople, the Balkans, and Germany.
Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873; American Academy of Arts and Sciences.; Dudley Observatoy; Foulke, William Parker, 1816-1865; Fraley, F., (Frederick), 1804-1901; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903; Miskey, William F.; Peirce, Benjamin, 1809-1880; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.; Winslow, C. F.; Morphology.; Science.
- Papers, 1850-1864
  Scope and Contents note
  255 pieces, manuscript. The collection consists of letters written to and from John Warner, the major portion of which deal with a controversy which arose when Benjamin Peirce, of Harvard, after having seen Mr. Warner's manuscript pertaining to organic morphology, read a paper on the subject before the Providence meeting of the AAAS, 1855. In addition to the chief topic, the Papers contain many comments on the "Harvard clique," its influence on the AAAS, a controversy involving the administration of the Dudley Observatory in Albany, and the U.S. Coast survey. For a complete list of the letters see Table of contents filed with the papers. Deposited by the Academy of natural sciences of Philadelphia, December 1944. Table of contents available.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 19, 1850; 8" x 10"; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Office, Sch[uylkill] Nav[igation] Co., A.L.S. 2p. Requests that an inventory be made of the cars.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 23, 1850; 8" x 10"; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Office, Sch[uylkill] Nav[igation] compy, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (Contains also draft of Warner's reply, Nov. 26,1850) Company matters relative to contracts.
  - Letter to F[rederick] Fraley, Nov. 26, 1850; 8" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A. draft of L. 1p. (On same sheet with letter from Fraley to Warner, Nov. 23, 1850) Explains misunderstanding about the making of contracts [Schuylkill navigation company].
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 20, 1850; 8" x 10"; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Office, Sch[uylkill] Nav[igation] compy, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Company matters.
  - Letter to F. Fraley, Dec. 21, 1850; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 3p. As directed will report to Mr. E.T. Warner. Report upon the use of the cars.
  - Letter to [E.T. Warner ?], Dec. 21, 1850; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. Is informed by Mr. Fraley that he is the present head of the Car department; awaits instructions for service.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 24, 1850; 8" x 10"; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
  - Letter to F. Fraley, Dec. 26, 1850; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. Will be glad for the opportunity to discuss with him the dissatisfaction relative to his work.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 28, 1851; 8" x 10"; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Office, Sch[uylkill] Nav[igation] co., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Dismissal from employ of the Company.
  - Letter to brother [John Warner], April 14, 1851; 8" x 10 1/2"; Warner, Redwood Fisher, b. 1818
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. Cost of pipe. Family news.
  - Letter to P.W. Sheafer, Feb. 14, 1853; 7 3/4" x 10"; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, Copy of L. 1p. (On Same sheet is letter from Agassiz to Sheafer, Feb. 22, 1853) Relative to fishes.
  - Letter to P.W. Sheafer, Feb. 22, 1853; 7 3/4" x 10"; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, Copy of L. 1p. (On same sheet with letter from Agassiz to Sheafer, Feb. 14, 1853.) Desires to obtain specimens of fish from the different creeks in Sheafer's vicinity.
  - Letter to John Warner, May 25, 1853; 8" x 10"; Peck, William G. (William Guy), 1820-1892
    West Point, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Contains pencil notes by John Warner (?). Comments on Mr. Warner's mathematical studies; advice with respect to publishing same; mentions AAAS.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 1, 1853; 8 1/2" x 10 3/4" and 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Smithsonian inst. A.L.S. 2p. and enc. - 2p. Encloses report upon paper submitted to the Institution for publication.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 19, 1853; 8" x 10"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Washington, L.S. 2p. Relative to a paper submitted to the Smithsonian institution for publication.
  - Letter to P.W. Sheaffer, 1853?; 8" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    [ca.] A.L. 17p. Incomplete? Transmits a few hints which will enable him to understand his views in relation to the diagrams submitted to his inspection [re organic morphology].
  - Letter to John Warner, March 8, 1854; 8" x 10"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Washington, L.S. 1p. Relative to a manuscript submitted to the Smithsonian institution for publication
  - Letter to John Warner, April 4, 1854; 8 1/2" x 11"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Delaware college, Newark, A.L.S. 1p. Comments upon Warner's mathematical researches.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 3, 1854; 8" x 10"; Longstreth, Miers Fisher, -1891
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Comments upon a paper Mr. Warner submitted to him.
  - Letter to P.W. Sheafer, June 24, 1855; 4 3/4" x 7 1/2", 8" x 12 1/2"; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Nahant, Copy of L. - 2c. of 1p. each. (On same sheet with 2nd c. is letter from Benjamin Peirce to D. Washburn, July 16, 1857) Promises to return math. papers. Desires the different kinds of minnows of Sheafer's neighborhood.
  - Letter to [John Warner], Nov. 3, 1855; 8" x 10"; Fisher, Charles Henry
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to an article on anthracite sent for publication in the American mining chronicle, iron manufacturers' & railway journal.
  - Letter to John Warner, November 10, 1855; 7 3/4" x 10"; Warner, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Family news. Offers to help him to get established in some business.
  - Letter to brother [John Warner], Nov. 11, 1855; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, Redwood Fisher, b. 1818
    Walnut lane, A.L.S. 3p. Family news.
  - Letter to [John Warner], Dec. 5, 1855; 8" x 10"; Fisher, Charles Henry
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the publication of his article on the anthracite coal fields in the American mining chronicle, iron manufacturers' & railway journal.
  - Letter to [John Warner?], 1856; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Combescure, Édouard
    [ca.] A.L.S. 4p. (Accompanied by ms. copy - 3p. and end.) In French Relative to curved lines. (Original signature confusing - might it be Charles Jules Felix de Comberousse, 1826-1897?]
  - Letter to [John Warner], Jan. 19, 1856; 4 1/2" x 7 3/4"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington,Ind. [i.e. 1857?]. A.L.S. 1p. Encloses document which he hopes will be satisfactory [Document is probably letter from Kirkwood to ---- Dec. 31, 1856 which was pasted to the above letter when received by the A.P.S.]
  - Letter to John Warner, March 18, 1856; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jeanes, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Believes Mr. Warner is more fitted for scientific than mercantile pursuits.
  - Letter to John Warner, Oct. 7, 1856; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Newark, A.L.S. 1p. Comments on Warner's Organic morphology. Has accepted the professorship of mathematics in Indiana university.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Oct. 17, 1856; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Poole, Henry W. (Henry Ward), 1825-1890
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Mr. Warner's mathematical calculations.
  - Letter to W. Parker Foulke, Nov. 3, 1856; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 5p. At Foulke's requests, describes his researches upon the properties of curved lines; mentions using the library of the American philosophical society.
  - Letter to L. Agassiz, Dec. 1, 1856; 8" x 10"; Sheafer, P. W. (Peter Wenrick), b. 1819
    Pottsville, Copy of L. 1p. (On same sheet is copy of Letter from J. Warner to L. Agassiz, Dec. 1, 1856) (3c. of each) Encloses a letter from Mr. Warner the author of a paper on forms.
  - Letter to Louis Agassiz, Dec. 1, 1856; 8" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 2p. (On same sheet with copy of letter from P.W. Sheafer to Agassiz, Dec. 1, 1856. Contains also notes by Warner relative to the correspondence) (3c. of each) Requests that he return the paper on organic forms sent him three years before
  - Letter to J[ohn] Warner, Dec. 8, 1856; 5" x 8"; Cogswell, Joseph Green, 1786-1871
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Whereabouts of M. Combescure.
  - Letter to Elias Schneider, Dec. 18, 1856; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A. copy of L. S. 1p. and end. Desires to verify a date with reference to a certain paper Mr. Warner had submitted to the Smithsonian institution.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Dec. 20, 1856; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schneider, Elias
    Orwigsburg [Pa.] A.L.S. 1p. Dates certain remarks by Prof. Henry as being made during the school convention in August 1853.
  - Letter to Dan[ie]l Kirkwood, Dec. 22, 1856; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. and end. Asks him to give a statement about his knowledge of Warner's researches in the organic generation of curves and the science of morphology.
  - Letter to J. P. Lesley, Dec. 22, 1856; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. (copy of same) Conjectures as to how far he may be considered a pioneer in the science of organic morphology in this country.
  - Letter to ---- ----, Dec. 31, 1856; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Indiana university, A.L.S. 2p. Relative to John Warner and his mathematical studies. [Probably enclosed with letter to John Warner, Jan. 19,1857]
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 25, Jan. 1, 1856, 1857; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jeanes, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Comments of P. Lesley on Mr. Warner's work on organic morphology.
  - Letter to Saml. Bowles, Dec., 1857; 6" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy. (cf. also letter of Dec. 26, 1857)
  - Letter to brother [W.W. Whitcomb?], March, 1857; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Sheafer, P. W. (Peter Wenrick), b. 1819
    Pottsville, Copy L. 1p. and end. The Peirce-[Warner] controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 27, Dec. 4,6,7, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 28p. Relative to the Peirce-Winslow and Peirce-Warner controversies. Describes his life and works.
  - Letter to [David A.] Wells, Feb. 18, 1857; 8" x 12 1/2"; Vaughan, Daniel, ca. 1821-1879
    Cincinnati, Copy of L. 2p. Plagiarism of Prof. Peirce. His action relative to publication of an essay which he hopes may have some effect in bringing the reign of scientific despotism to a close. The AAAS.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Feb. 21, 1857; 5" x 8"; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. Advice with respect to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to P.W. Sheafer, March 7, 1857; 8" x 12 1/2"; Whitcomb, W. W.
    Boston, Copy of L. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to P.W. Sheafer, March 24, 1857; 4 3/4" x 7 1/2"; Whitcomb, W. W.
    Boston, Copy of L. 2p. and end. Relative to the Peirce-[Warner] controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, April 21, 1857; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jeanes, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 1, 1857; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Miskey, William F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the publication of his book.
  - Letter to D. Washburn, July 16, 1857; 8" x 9 1/2"; Peirce, Benjamin, 1809-1880
    Harvard university Copy of L. 1p. (Another copy of this letter is found on the same sheet with letter from Agassiz to P.W. Sheafer, June 24, 1855, c.2) Acknowledges John Warner's work upon organic morphology, printed by order of the [Pottsville scientific] association.
  - Letter to John Warner, Aug. 8, 1857; 6 1/4" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 3p. Acknowledges Warner's Studies in organic morphology; comments upon it.
  - Letter to the Boston Traveller, Aug. 18, 1857; 8" x 12 1/2"; Glenn, D.
    Andover, L. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Winslow controversy, and a similar one between Peirce and Bond.
  - Letter to C. F. Winslow, Aug. 19, 1857; 7 1/4" x 11 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Smethport,Pa., A. copy of L.S. 2p. and end. Solicits his advice relative to the procedure to follow in trying to recover an original memoir upon organic morphology which was intended for presentation at the Providence meeting of the AAAS.
  - Letter to John Warner, Aug. 22, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Will send his letter to the editors of thef Boston Traveller in an effort to recover his manuscript [Peirce-Warner controversy].
  - Letter to John Warner, Aug. 23, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Relative to the [Peirce-Warner controversy].
  - Letter to John Warner, Aug. 29, 1857; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Warner, Sept. 3, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 6p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy and his own controversy with Prof. Peirce.
  - Letter to [John Warner], Sept. 13, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy and his own controversy with Prof. Peirce.
  - Letter to [John Warner], Sept. 19, [1857]; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. The Peirce-Winslow controversy; the AAAS.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 20, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner and Peirce-Winslow controversies.
  - Letter to John Warner, Oct. 2, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner and Peirce Winslow controversies. Report on some fossil bones by Prof. Leidy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Oct. 13, 1857; 7 3/4" x 10"; Jeanes, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the distribution of his "tracts"; mentions the American philosophical society.
  - Letter to John Warner, Oct. 13, 1857; 8" x 10"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
  - Letter to [John Warner], Oct. 24, 1857; 8" x 10"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Warner, Oct. 25, 1857; 4 1/2" x 7"; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Oct. 27, 1857; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 5, 1857; 5" x 8"; Jones, N. F.
    Smethport, A.L.S. 1p. Mentions the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 5, [1857]; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Statement that a copy of a paper on organic morphology by John Warner had been sent to Prof. Agassiz and had been duly acknowledged, Nov. 7, 1857; 6" x 8"; Sheafer, P. W. (Peter Wenrick), b. 1819
    Pottsville, A.D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 11, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 8p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to the editors of Silliman's Journal, Nov. 19, 1857; 6" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Beaver Valley, Pa., A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. Has been informed that the Journal's notice of his work,"Studies in orgnaic morphology," attributed the authorship to one Warren; asks that a correction be made.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 24, 1857; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 3p. Accompanied by copy of same - 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 25, 1857; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 8, 1857; 5" x 7 1/2"; Bowles, Samuel, 1826-1878
    Springfield, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for statement of facts in case with the Cambridge professor [charges of scientific piracy against Benjamin Peirce].
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 8, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy. Desires to know more about Warner's researches.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 18, 1857; 4 1/2" x 7"; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and envelope. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to Dan[ie]l Kirkwood, Dec. 19, 1857; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A. copy of L.S. 2p. The Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to C. Loeser, Dec. 19, 1857; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 21, 1857; 5" x 8"; Bowles, Samuel, 1826-1878
    [Springfield,] Mass., A.L.S. 1p. and newsclipping. Relative to charges of scientific piracy against Benjamin Peirce.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 21, 1857; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 23, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy. Warner's mathemtical studies.
  - Letter to Horace Greeley, Dec. 24, 1857; 6" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. In pencil. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to W. W. Whitcomb, Dec. 24, 1857; 6" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L. 2p. Relative to the [Peirce-Warner controversy].
  - Letter to [John Warner], Dec. 25, 1857; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
  - Letter to Saml. Bowles, Dec. 26, 1857; 7 1/2" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy. (cf. also Warner's letter to Bowles, dated Dec. 1857)
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 30, 1857; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Mentions the panic dullness. The gas companies of the city.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Dec. 29, [1857]; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. The Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Warner, Dec. 30, 1857; 5" x 8"; Whitcomb, W. W.
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Nov. 21, 22, 1857; 8" x 10"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 6p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner and Peirce-Winslow controversies.
  - Letter to [W. W. Whitcomb], March 3, 1857(?); 5" x 8"; Sheafer, P. W. (Peter Wenrick), b. 1819
    Pottsville, Copy of L. 2p. Asks him to call on Prof. Agassiz to reclaim a manuscript submitted by John Warner.
  - Letter to [John Warner], October 29, 1857?; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    New York, Thursday []. A.L.S. 2p. Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - [Miscellaneous notes pertaining to the loss of his manuscript on morphology which had been submitted to Louis Agassiz by P.W. Sheafer, 1857-1858; 8" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    extracts from various meetings of the AAAS.] [ca.] A.D. 13p. Pencil and ink.
  - Letter to [John Warner], 1857-1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    ca. A.L. 4p. incomplete. The Peirce-Winslow and Peirce-Warner controversies.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, 1858; 5" x 8"; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    [ca.] A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, 1858; 5" x 8"; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    [ca.] A.L.S. 4p. Comments on a paper recently submitted to him by Mr. Warner.
  - Letter to R.L.M. Cambden(sic), 1858; 8" x 10 1/2"; Warner,John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L. 6p. Reviews of his work on morphology; gives summary of the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to R.L.M. Cambden (sic), March, 1858; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. Sends copies of his pamphlet on Organic morphology to be distributed. Refers to the [Peirce-Warner controversy].
  - Letter to W. W. Whitcomb, Jan. 7, 1858; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. and end. Relative to the [Peirce-Warner controversy].
  - Letter to brother [John Warner], Jan. 10, 1858; 6 1/2" x 8"; Warner, Redwood Fisher, b. 1818
    Germantown, A.L.S. 4p. Family news.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 12, 1858; 6 1/4" x7 3/4"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 12, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to brother [John Warner], Jan. 13, 1858; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, Redwood Fisher, b. 1818
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. Relationship between John Warner and his family.
  - Letter to [John Warner], Jan. 13, 1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 8p. The Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 20, 1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 18p. His scientific and philosophical conclusions.
  - Letter to Horace Greeley, Jan. 25, 1858; 6 1/4" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. Relative to a published statement [in re the Peirce-Warner controversy].
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 27, 1858; 5" x 8"; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to Horace Greeley, Jan. 30, 1858; 6" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L. 4p. Gives a summary of his controversy with Prof. Peirce with regard to his work on morphology.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 31, 1858; 5" x 8"; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 7, 1858; 4 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Plans to resume practice in Massachusetts. The Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 13, 1858; 5" x 8"; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 14, 1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 12p. Suggests sending his pamphlets to R.L.M. Camden, Paris, for distribution. Sends copies of some of his own works. Has about decided to settle in West Newton. Comments on lawyers. Peirce - Winslow controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 16, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to Horace Greeley, Feb. 16, 1858; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. The Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 22, 1858; 8" x 10"; Jeanes, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Relative to the distribution of copies of his Organic Morphology; mentions the American philosophical society.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 23, 1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 14p. The Peirce-Winslow controversy. The politics of the AAAS.
  - Letter to John Warner, March 1, 1858; 8" x 10"; Jeanes, Joseph